Autograph File, B: Guide.
Autograph File, B,
ca.1500-1976.
Houghton Library, Harvard College Library, Harvard University
24 boxes (12 linear ft.)
The Autograph File is an alphabetically arranged collection of single letters, manuscripts, and drawings received from various sources at various times. Additions continue to be made.
Received from various sources at various times. Accession information is given with the item entry. The most recent addition to this portion of the Autograph File was made 2012 August 20.
Arranged alphabetically by author.
The Autograph File is a collection of items received singly or in small groups from various sources at various times, and autograph collections, such as that of Evert J. Wendell, which were not kept together as a distinct collection. Items in this portion of the Autograph File include letters from Joanna Baillie, Charles Baudelaire, Benjamin Disraeli earl of Beaconsfield, Hector Berlioz, Frederic Mayer Bird, Bishop Phillips Brooks, Elizabeth Barrett Browning, Robert Browning, William Jennings Bryan, and Aaron Burr. There are also compositions and letters of Honore de Balzac, Sir James Matthew Barrie, Henry Ward Beecher, Julius Bing, the Bonaparte family, the Bronte family, William Cullen Bryant, Robert Burns, and Lord Byron, among others.
- B., Capt. Letter from Capt. B. to Lord H. F. Ms poem; [n.p., n.d.], 1s.(4p.)
  Poem is addressed to "Harry".
  *2002M-16. Removed from Lowell 1710.5.
- B., John A.L.s. to Ellen [ ]; St. Louis, Missouri, 7 Aug 1853., 1s.(3p.)
  No date or source.
- Babbage, Charles, 1792-1871. A.L.s. to [ ] Ticknor; [n.p. n.d.], 1s.(2p.)
- Babbidge, Charles. A.L.s. to [George Pearce] Guerrier; Pepperell, 27 Jun 1881., 1s.(1p.) env.
  *43M-537. Presented by Miss Edith Guerrier, 18 Feb 1944.
- Babbitt, Dora Drew. A.L.s.to John Cournos; Boston, 7 Dec 1940., 1s.(2p.) env.
  About Irving Babbitt.
  *59M-87. Gift of John Cournos, 17 Sept 1959.
- Babbitt, Irving, 1865-1933. A.L.s. to Elizabeth Gaskell Norton; Sorrento, 18 Apr 1928., 1s.(2p.) env.
  *53M-72. Presented by Miss Elizabeth Norton, 3 Dec 1953.
- Babcock, Orville E., 1835-1884. Letters to Adam Badeau:
  - A.L.s.; Lawrence, 4 May 1866., 2s.(6p.)
  - A.L.s.; Washington, 18 Jun 1870., 1s.(4p.)
  - A.L.s.; Washington, 4 Oct 1870., 1s.(4p.)
    Bequest of E.J. Wendell, 1918.
- Babcock, Orville E., 1835-1884. Letters to Adam Badeau:
  - A.L.s.; Washington, 10 Mar 1872., 1s.(4p.)
  - A.L.s.; Washington, 8 Aug 1872., 1s.(2p.)
  - A.L.s.; Washington, 2 Feb 1873., 1s.(4p.)
  - A.L.s.; Washington, 12 Feb 1873., 1s.(3p.)
- Babcock, Orville E., 1835-1884. Letters to Adam Badeau:
  - A.L.s.; Washington, 25 Apr 1874., 1s.(3p.)
  - A.L.s.; Washington, 31 May 1874., 2s.(4p.)
  - A.L.s.; Long Branch, 6 Jul 1874., 1s.(3p.)
  - A.L.s.; Long Branch 30 Jul 1874., 1s.(1p.)
- Babcock, Orville E., 1835-1884. Letters to Adam Badeau:
  - A.L.s.; Washington, 20 Dec 1874., 1s.(4p.)
  - A.L.s.; Washington, 11 Jan 1875., 1s.(2p.)
  - A.L.s.; Washington, 9 Apr 1875., 1s.(3p.)
  - A.L.s.; Washington, 25 Apr 1875., 1s.(4p.)
- Babcock, Orville E., 1835-1884. Letters to Adam Badeau:
  - A.L.s.; Washington, 31 Oct 1876., 2s(2p)
  - A.L.s.; Washington, 5 Mar 1877., 1s(4p)
  - A.L.s.; Washington, 8 Mar 1877., 1s(2p)
  - A.L.s.; Washington, 10 Nov 1878., 1s(2p)
- [Bach, Carl Philipp Emanuel, 1714-1788]. Mein vater. A.MS (unsigned); [n.p., 17--?], 1s.(1p.)
  In German.
  *47M-313. Gift of G.B. Weston, in memory of Meriel Dimick Weston, 23 June 1948.
- Bache, Alexander Dallas, 1806-1867. A.L.s. to John Russell Barllett; Washington, 12 Mar 1849., 1s.(1p.)
- Bachman, John, 1790-1874. A.L.s. to [Mrs Jacob F.] Roh; Schagticoke, 30 Aug 1823., 2s.(6p.)
  About the death of Mr Roh.
- Bachman, John, 1790-1874. A.L.s. to Jacob Sass; Stillwater, 26 Aug 1823., 1s.(4p.)
  About the death of Jacob F. Roh.
- Bachman, John, 1790-1874. [Directions to find his residence] A.MS. (3d person); Schagticoke[1823], 1s.(1p.)
- Bachman, John, 1790-1874. [Epitaph on Jacob F. Roh] A.MS. (unsigned); [Schagticoke,1823], 1s.(1p.)
- Bachrach, Louis Fabian, 1881-1963. Letter to Justice Oliver Wendell Holmes,1926 Nov. 11., 1 folder
  *98M-54 Removed from *AC9.H7375.Zz640j v.2/3.
- Back, W A.L.s. to [Mrs ] Turner; [n.p.] May 1821., 1s.(4p.)
- Backus, Isaac, 1724-1806. A.L.s.to John Rippon; Middleboro, 10 Nov 1798., 1s.(4p.)
  Removed from *41-871.
  Purchased with assistance from the Friends of the Library, 1941.
- Backus, James A.D.s.(initials); Norwich, 9 Feb 1793., 1s.(1p.)
- Bacon, Daniel C. Letters to Ebenezer Bacon:
  - A.L.s.; Boston, 15 Apr 1850., 1s.(4p.)
  - A.L.s.; Boston, 20 Apr 1850., 1s.(4p.)
  - A.L.s.; Boston, 7 May 1850., 1s.(4p.)
  - A.L.s.; Boston, 10 Jul 1850., 1s.(2p.)
  - A.L.s.; Boston, Aug 1850., 1s.(4p.)
    Gift of Mrs. Gaspar Bacon, 11 Mar 1911.
- Bacon, Daniel C Letters to Thatcher T. Payne:
  - A.L.s.; Boston, 3 Mar 1843., 1s.(3p.)
  - A.L.s.; Boston, 12 Jun 1843., 1s.(3p.)
    Gift of Mrs. Gaspar Bacon, 11 Mar 1941.
- Bacon, Daniel C Letters to [Mrs. ] Payne:
  - A.L.s.; Boston, 31 Aug 1841., 1s.(3p.)
  - A.L.s.; Boston, 1 May 1843., 1s.(4p.)
  - A.L.s.; Boston, 4 Dec 1843., 1s.(4p.)
    Gift of Mrs. Gaspar Bacon. 11 Mar 1941.
- Bacon, Daniel C Letters to [Mrs. ] Payne:
  - A.L.s.; Boston, 14 Jan 1844., 1s.(4p.)
  - A.L.s.; Boston, 26 Jun 1844., 1s.(4p.)
  - A.L.s.; Boston, 31 Aug 1844., 1s.(3p.)
- Bacon, Daniel C Letters to [Mrs. ] Payne:
  - A.L.s.; Boston, 7 Feb 1846., 1s.(4p.)
  - A.L.s.; Boston, 18 Sep 1849., 1s.(1p.)
  - A.L.s.; Boston, 18 Jan 1854., 1s.(2p.)
  - A.L.s.; Boston, 4 Aug 1856., 1s.(2p.)
- Bacon, Daniel C A.L.s. to Eloise [ ]; Boston, 23 May 1835., 1s.(2p.)
- Bacon, Francis, viscount St. Albans, 1561-1626. A.L.s. to [ ]; [n.p.] 13 Jul 1607., 1s.(1p.)
  This is in colotype.
- Bacon, John, 1737-1820. A.L.s.to [ ] Phillips; Stockbridge, 27 Sep 1785., 1s.(4p.)
  *42M-1341. Presented by the estate of Grenville Lindall Winthrop, June 1943.
- Bacon, Leonard, 1802-1881. A.L.s. to Augustus Russell Street; [n.p., n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
- Bacon, Leonard, 1802-1881. A.L.s. to Josiah Strong; New Haven, 21 Oct 1879., 2s.(6p.)
- Bacon, Robert, 1860-1919. T.L. to Alvey Augustus Adee; [n.p.] 1 Aug 190-., 1s.(1p.)
- Bacon, Robert, 1860-1919. T.L.(copy) to David Jayne Hill; [n.p.] 16 Mar 1910., 1s.(1p.)
- Bacon, Robert, 1860-1919. T.L.(copy) to Esme William Howard; [n.p.] 11 Nov 1908., 1s.(1p.)
- Bacon, Robert, 1860-1919. Telegram to [ ] McIntyre; Washington, 5 Aug 1908., 1s.(1p.)
  Gift of Mrs. Gaspar Bacon, 11 Mar 1941
- Bacon, Robert, 1860-1919. Telegram to [ ] Magoon; Washington, 5 Aug 1908., 1s.(1p.)
- Bacon, Robert, 1860-1919. T.L.(corrected copy) to Prince Murat; Paris, 17 Oct 1911., 1s.(1p.)
- Bacon, Robert, 1860-1919. Telegram to R H Post; Washington, 4 Aug 1908., 1s.(1p.)
- Bacon, Robert, 1860-1919. Letters to Whitelaw Reid:
  - Telegram; Washington, 19 Feb 1909., 1s.(1p.)
  - T.L. (copy); [n.p.] 5 Mar 1909., 2s.(2p.)
- Bacon, Robert, 1860-1919. T.L.s. to Theodore Roosevelt; Washington, 25 Jun 1906., 1s.(1p.)
  Note added in Roosevelt's hand.
- Bacon, Robert, 1860-1919. T.L.(corrected copy) to [ ]; Paris, 17 Oct 1911., 1s.(2p.)
- Bacon, T. S. A.L.s. to [Henry Ainsworth] Parker; Buckystone, 2 May 1898., 1s.(4p.)
  *61M-87. Purchased with the Keller and Bemis funds from E.R. Smith Book Service, Sept-Oct 1961.
- Baden-Powell, Robert Baden-Powell, baron, 1857-1941. T.L.s.to Sir Frederic Nathan; London, 25 Feb 1914., 1s.(1p.)
  *60M-136. Gift of Mr. Mrs. J. F. Fleming, Dec 1960.
- Baden-Powell, Robert Stephenson Smith Baden-Powell, baron, 1857-1941. A.L.s. to [ ] Paton; Kent, 2 May 1917., 1s.(1p.)
  *52M-57. Presented by Miss Helen Cam, 2 Oct 1952.
- Baden-Powell, Robert Stephenson Smith Baden-Powell, baron, 1857-1941. A.L.s. to [ ] Whitehouse; in the train, 13 [Feb?] 1907., 1s.(1p.)
- Badger, Richard Saltonstall, b.1772. A.L.s. to Nathaniel Saltonstall; New York, 11 Sep 1794., 1s.(3p.)
  *48M-325. Kinsman Papers. Presented by Mrs. Gamaliel Bradford, 27 May 1942.
- Badger, George, b.1785. A.L.s. to Nathaniel Saltonstall; [Providence, 9 May 1806], 1s.(3p.)
  *48M-324. Kinsman Papers. Presented by Mrs. Gamaliel Bradford, 27 May 1942.
- Badger, George, b.1785. A.L.s. to Nathaniel Saltonstall; New York, 20 Apr 1808., 1s.(3p.)
- Bagot, Richard, 1860-1921. A.L.s. to [Miss ] Cochrane; Rome, 14 May 1901., 1s.(4p.)
- Bahr, Hermann, 1863-1934. 3 letters to Julius Bab:
  - Vienna, 4 Feb 1906., 1s.(2p.) env.
  - Same, 1 Mar 1906., 1s.(2p.)
  - Same, 30 Dec 1910., 1s.(4p.)
    *44M-190-192. Purchased from Theo Feldman, 4 Dec 1944.
- Bailey, G. Receipt for loan of $2000: autograph manuscript document (signed); Washington D.C., 1855 February 19., 1s.(2p.)
  No accession number. Found with: MS Storage 281. Collection materials assembled by Carolyn Jakeman.
- Bailey, Gamaliel, 1807-1859. A.L.s. to Elizur Wright; Cincinnati, 20 Feb 1838., 1s.(2p.)
  Concerns the Quarterly anti-slavery magazine.
  C1 6641F(2)
  By exchange. 24 Feb 1939.
- Bailey, Gamaliel, 1807-1859. A.L.s.to Elizur Wright; Washington, 7 Oct 1851., 1s.(3p.)
  *60M-216. Purchased from Mr. Harvey S. Teal, Mar 1961.
- Bailey, James Montgomery, 1841-1894. A.L.s. to Benjamin W. Austin; Danbury, 24 Apr 1887., 1s.(1p.)
  Also a portrait and a clipping.
- Bailey, Philip James, 1816-1902. [Portrait: photograph signed]; Nottingham[1902]
  *42M-1050. Presented by Thomas Bailey Aldrich Memorial Trustees, 7 June 1943.
- Bailey, Theodorus, 1752-1828. A.L.s. to [ ]; Poughkeepsie, 10 Nov 1700., 1s.(1p.)
- Baillie, Joanna, 1762-1851. A.L.s. to [ ]; Hampstead, 11 Jun [n.d.], 1s.(2p.)
  *45M-181(22) Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Baillie, Joanna, 1762-1851. A.L.s. to [ ]; Hampstead[1817?], 1s.(4p.)
  *54M-151. Purchased from Mrs. Rose Carhard Cheeseman, 9 Nov 1954.
- Baillie, Joanna, 1762-1851. A.L.s.to Lady [ ] Bunbury; Hampstead, 23 Sep [18--], 1s.(4p.)
  *56M-135. Purchased with the Lowell fund from Hamill Barker, Dec 1956.
- Baillie, Joanna, 1762-1851. A.L.s.to [J D ]; Hampstead, 27 Jun [1848], 1s.(3p.)
  *56M-137. Purchased with the Lowell fund from Hamill Barker, Dec 1956.
- Baillie, Joanna, 1762-1851. A.L.s.to [Mrs ] Greaves; Hampstead [13 Feb 1829], 1s.(4p.)
  *56M-134. Purchased with the Lowell fund from Hamill Barker, Dec 1956.
- Baillie, Joanna, 1762-1851. A.L.s. to [Felicia Dorothea (Browne)] Hemans; Hampstead, 4 Jun 1828., 1s.(4p.)
  Norton autographs, 15 Jul 1914.
- Baillie, Joanna, 1762-1851. 2 A.L.s. to Sophia Milligan:
  - A.L.s.; Hampstead, 15 Dec 1837., 1s.(4p.)
  - A.L.s.; Hampstead, 9 Aug [1838], 2s.(6p.)
    *54M-152. Purchased from Mrs. Rose Carhard Cheeseman, 9 Nov 1954.
- Baillie, Joanna, 1762-1851. A.L.s. to [ ] Rogers; [n.p., 1832], 1s.(3p.)
  *45M-181 (21). Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Baillie, Joanna, 1762-1851. A.L.s. to [ ] Sedgewick; Hampstead, 30 Aug [n.d.], 1s.(4p.)
  *45M-181 (20). Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Baillie, Joanna, 1762-1851. A.L.s.to [Mrs] Sotheby; Hampstead, 29 Nov [18--], 1s.(4p.)
  *56M-136. Purchased with the Lowell fund from Hamill Barker, Dec 1956.
- Baillie, Matthew, 1761-1823. A.L.s. to [ ] Adams; [London] 21 Oct [ ], 1s.(2p.)
- Baillie, Mathew, 1761-1823. MS.D.s. (initials); [London] 26 Apr 1813., 1s. (1p.)
  Prescription for Sir Brent Spencer; also initialled by Sir Henry Halford.
  Gift of E. J. Wendell, 1918.
- Bailly, Jean Sylvain, 1736-1793. A.L.s. to [ ]; [Paris, n.d], 1s.(1p.)
  *49M-187 (18). From the Collection of French Academicians formed by M. Victor Deseglise, ca. 1920.
- Baily, John Walker, 1809-1873. A.L.s. to Charles Roach Smith; London 11 Sep 1865., 1s.(2p.)
- Bain, Alexander, 1818-1903. A.L.s. to Henry Holt Co.; Aberdeen, 12 Feb 1874., 1s.(2p.)
  *69M-102 Gift of Rev. Donald F. Winslow, Mar 1970.
- Bainbridge, William, 1774-1833. MS.L.s. to Josiah Barker; Charlestown, 7 Nov 1813., 1s. (3p.)
  Bequest of Justin Winsor, 1899.
- Bainbridge, William,1774-1833. A.L.s. to [John] Jeffries; Charlestown, 25 Jun 1814., 1s.(2p.)
  *50M-340. Gift of Dr. James H. Means, 30 Mar 1951.
- Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887. A.L.s. to Dr. William Prescott; Framingham, [n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
  *45M-181(23). Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Baker, Christina (Hopkinson) A.L.s.to Odell Shepard; New Haven, 30 Sep 1937., 1s.(4p.) env.
  *61M-50. Gift of Odell Shepard, Oct 1961.
- Baker, George, 1915- A.L.s. to [Mrs.] Elizabeth Pouzzner; Los Angeles, 18 Sep [n.d.], 2s.(2p.)
  *52M-147. Presented by Mrs. Benjamin F. Pouzzner, 23 Dec 1952.
- Baker, George Melville, 1832-1875. A.L.s. to Thomas Clifford; Boston, 24 Feb 1873., 1s.(1p.)
- Baker, George Pierce, 1866-1935. T.L.s.to [George Lyman] Kittredge; Cambridge, 8 Jan 1923., 1s.(1p.)
  From the Kittredge estate, 1942.
- Baker, George Pierce, 1866-1935. T.L.s. to [ ] Morgan; Cambridge, 7 Jan 1897., 1s.(2p.)
- Baker, Lewis A.L.s. to Benjamin Austin; Nicaragua, 26 Jan 1894., 1s.(1p.)
  Also a portrait.
- Balch, Thomas Willing, 1866-1927. 2 A.L.s.to Robert Treat Paine; Philadelphia, 20 Apr and 1 May 1903., 2s.(6p.)
- Baldwin, Christopher Columbus, 1800-1835. A.L.s. to Joshua Coffin; [Cambridge] 2 Oct 1832., 1s.(4p.)
  contains copy of letter from Henry Hale, 1730.
  Enclosed is A.L.s. from Wendell Phillips Garrison to [Justin] Winsor.
  Gift of Wendell P. Garrison, 2 Jan 1897.
- Baldwin, Henry, 1780-1844. 2 A.L.s.to Stephen Barlow:
  - [N.p.] 6 Feb 1813., (1); 1s.(3p.)
  - [N.p.] 16 Feb 1813., (2); 1s.(2p.)
    *57M-147. Manuscripts supplementing the Barlow Collection, n.d.
- Baldwin, Henry, 1780-1844. A.L.s. to Thomas Worthington; [n.p.] 23 Feb 1812., 1s.(2p.)
  Recat. fr. X4.3PF.
- Baldwin, Henry Porter. A. signature; Lansing, 30 Mar 1871., 1s.(1p.)
  Recat. fr. X 5.3*.
- Baldwin, Loammi, 1780-1838. A.L.s. to Timothy Bigelow; Groton, 7 Mar 1803., 1s. (2p.)
  *69M-108. From the Davis Library, Nov 1969.
- Baldwin, Raymond Earl, 1893- T.L.s. to Eliot F. Bartlett; [Washington] 2 Mar 1948., 1s.(1p.)
  *50M-596. Presented by Eliot Bartlett, 16 July 1949.
- Baldwin, Raymond Earl, 1893- T.L.s. to Eliot F Bartlett; [Washington] 5 Apr 1948., 1s.(1p.)
  Enclosed is c.c. of T.L. from E.P. Munson. to R.E. Baldwin.
  *50M-597. Presented by Eliot Bartlett, 16 July 1949.
- Baldwin, Roger Sherman, 1793-1863. A.L.s. to Benjamin Robbins Curtis; [n.p., n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
- Balestier, Charles Wolcott, 1861-1891. Typescript letter (signed) to [William Morton] Fullerton; Isle of Wight, 1891 August 28., 1s.(1p.)
  Mentions Henry James and other matters.
- Balfour, Arthur James Balfour, 1st earl of, 1848-1930. MS.L.s. to William B. Fitts; [London] 18 Jul 1899., 1s.(4p.)
  *43M-198. Purchased with the Sheldon fund from Mrs. Russell Law, 27 Oct 1943.
- Balfour, Arthur James Balfour, 1st earl of, 1848-1930. T.L.s. to Oliver Wendell Holmes; Geneva, 11 Sep 1922., 1s.(1p.) env.
  *50-790. Gift of Mrs. Edward Jackson Holmes, Jan 1951.
- Balfour, Arthur James Balfour, 1st earl of, 1848-1930. T.L.s.(photostatic copy) to Abbott Lawrence Lowell; [London] 18 Dec 1918., 1s.(2p.)
  Letter of thanks for service of Harvard medical unit.
  Harvard Surgical Unit, 3 Dec 1919.
- Balfour, Arthur James Balfour, 1st earl of, 1848-1930. MS.L.s. to [ ] Paton; Prestonkirk [Scotland] 4 Oct 1889., 1s.(2p.)
- Balfour, Arthur James Balfour, 1st earl of, 1848-1930. MS.L.s. to William Henry Rideing; [London] 7 Mar 1890., 1s.(4p.)
  *43M-199. Purchased with the Sheldon fund from Mrs. Russell Law, 27 Oct 1943.
- Ball, Edward, 1792-1873. Ballad A.MS.s.; [n.p., n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
  Bequest to E.J. Wendell, 1918.
- Ball, Sir Robert Stawell, 1840-1913. A.L.s. to [ ]; Cambridge, 18 Apr 18?3., 1s.(2p.)
  Also a newspaper clipping.
- Ball, Thomas, 1819-1911. A.L.s. to Daniel C. French; Florence, 25 Apr 1877., 1s.(4p.) env.
  Bequest of E.J. Wendell. 1918.
- Ball, Thomas, 1819-1911. A.L.s. to James Atkins Noyes; Montclair N.J., 27 Nov 1908., 2s.(2p.)
  Concerns Ball's equestrian statue of Washington, in Boston.
  *54M-198. Presented by Miss Penelope Noyes, Jan 1955.
- Ball, Timothy Horton, 1826-1913. A.L.s. to Ben W. Austin; Crown Point, 3 Jun 1891., 1s.(1p.)
  Gift of E. J. Wendell 1918
- Ballam, Thomas A.L.s. to [ ]; Kensington Park, 24 Feb 1884., 1s.(4p.)
- Ballanche, Pierre Simon, 1776-1847. A.L.s. to [Messrs. Didot]; [n.p.,n.d], 1s.(1p.)
  *49M-187 (19). From the Collection of French Academicians formed by M. Victor Deseglise, ca. 1920.
- Ballantine, Edward, 1886- T.L.s. to Arthur Tillman Merritt; Vineyard Haven, 25 Feb 1971., 1s. (1p.)
  Transferred from the Music Library, 1977.
- Ballou, Hosea, 1771-1852. A.L.s. to Ruth Ballou; New York, 30 Oct 1834., 1s.(3p.)
- Ballou, Hosea, 1796-1861. A.L.s. to Maturin Murray Ballou; Medford, 27 Sep 1852., 1s.(1p.)
  Also a genealogy.
- Balmanno, Robert A.L.s. to Daniel Webster; New York, 1 Mar 1852., 1s.(1p.)
- Baltimore, Frederick Calvert, 7th baron, 1731-1771. A.L.s. to [George Onslow, 1st earl of Onslow]; [London] 17 Sep 1767., 2s.(2p.)
  This letter accompanied the gift of a copy of Baltimore's A tour to the east (1767)
  Removed from *51-564.
  Purchased with the Howe fund, 3 Dec 1951.
- Balzac, Honoré de, 1799-1850. A.L.s.to [Adolphe, marquis de Custine]; [n.p.,n.d.], 1s.(2p.)
  *49M-237. Purchased with the Duplicate fund from Prof. George B. Weston, 1950.
- Balzac, Honoré de, 1799-1850. A.L.s. to [ ] Furne; [n.p.] 11 May 1843., 1s. (2p.)
  *62M-131. Purchased with the Amy Lowell fund, Jan 1963.
- Balzac, Honoré de, 1799-1850. A.L.s.to [ ]; [n.p.] 3 May [n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
  *57M-93. Deposited by George Benson Weston, 27 Dec 1957. Later bequest.
- Balzac, Honoré de, 1799-1850. A.L.s. to [Ildefonse Rousset]; Paris, 31 Jul 1848., 1s.(1p.)
  *42M-499 (4). Presented by Dr. Harris Kennedy, 26 Jan 1943.
- Bancroft, Amos A.L.s. to John Locke; Groton, 8 Nov 1827., 1s.(1p.)
- Bancroft, George, 1800-1891. T.L.s. to [ ]; Springfield, 1 Aug 1826., 1s.(1p.)
- Bancroft, George, 1800-1891. MS.L.s. to [ ]; Newport, 23 Aug 1853., 1s.(1p.); mounted.
- Bancroft, George, 1800-1891. A.L.s. to Charles Deane; New York, 21 Oct 1856., 1s.(3p.)
- Bancroft, George, 1800-1891. MS.L.s. to [ ]; New York, 2 May 1859., 1s.(1p.)
- Bancroft, George, 1800-1891. A.L.s. to [ ]; New York, 3 Dec 1864., 1s.(2p.)
- Bancroft, George, 1800-1891. A.L.s. to [ ]; Washington, 17 Oct 1874., 1s.(1p.)
- Bancroft, George, 1800-1891. A.L.s. to [Henry Alexander Scammell] Dearborn; Boston, 21 Sep 1842., 1s.(1p.)
  *42M-1293F. Gift of W. B. O. Field, Winter 1942.
- Bancroft, George, 1800-1891. A.L.s. to Charles Deane; New York, 9 Mar 1857., 1s.(1p.) env.
  Signature torn away.
- Bancroft, George, 1800-1891. A.L.s. to Charles Deane; New York, 25 Mar 1859., 1s.(4p.)
- Bancroft, George, 1800-1891. A.L.s. to [Mrs. ] Duncan; [n.p., n.d.], 1s.(2p.)
  Bequest of C.S. Sargent, 10 May 1927
- Bancroft, George, 1800-1891. A.L.s. to [ ] Eliot; Berlin, 25 Oct 1872., 1s.(1p.)
- Bancroft, George, 1800-1891. MS.L.s. to Edward Everett; Washington, 11 Mar 1845., 1s.(1p.)
  *50M-182. Presented by Richard L. Freeman, Esq., Nov 1950.
- Bancroft, George, 1800-1891. A.L.s. to T.W. Hammond; [Washington] 20 Mar 1875., 1s.(1p.)
- Bancroft, George, 1800-1891. MS.L.s. to Harper, firm, publishers; New York, 22 May 1855., 1s.(1p.)
- Bancroft, George, 1800-1891. A.L.s. to Russell Jarvis; Boston, 26 Jul 1823., 1s.(3p.)
- Bancroft, George, 1800-1891. MS.L.s. to Russell Jarvis; Washington, 16 Apr 1845., 1s.(1p.)
- Bancroft, George, 1800-1891. MS.L.s. to Robert Koenig; Berlin, 28 Sep 1872., 1s.(2p.)
- Bancroft, George, 1800-1891. A.L.s. to Johann Martin Lappenberg; Northampton, 20 Sep 1825., 1s.(4p.)
- Bancroft, George, 1800-1891. MS.L.s. to [Robert] Lemon; London, 20 Aug 1849., 1s.(3p.)
  *42M-499(5). Gift of Dr. Harris Kennedy, 26 Jan 1943.
- Bancroft, George, 1800-1891. A.L.s. to Orsamas Holmes Marshall; Washington, 6 Mar 1883., 1s.(1p.)
- Bancroft, George, 1800-1891. 1 letter to Justin Winsor;1883.
  Removed from US 2002.2, vol. I.
- Bancroft, George, 1800-1891. A.L.s. to [Charles] Nordhoff; [n.p.] 5 Jan 1875., 1s.(1p.)
- Bancroft, George, 1800-1891. MS.L.s. to [ ] Perry; Washington, 26 Apr 1875., 1s.(2p.)
- Bancroft, George, 1800-1891. A.L.s. to Alfred Smith; Berlin, 28 Jan 1873., 1s.(1p.)
- Bancroft, George, 1800-1891. A.L.s. to Douglas Taylor, New York, 28 Nov 1865., 1s.(1p.)
- Bancroft, George, 1800-1891. Mss. translation of poem from Shiller The Ideal. [n.p.,n.d.], 1s.(2p.)
  Also imitation from Shiller, The dignity of Woman. [n.p.,n.d.] 1s.(2p.)
  Norton autographs, 15 Jul 1940.
- Bancroft, George, 1800-1891. MS.L.s. to [ ] Thornton; Washington, 4 Apr 1875., 1s.(4p.)
- Bancroft, George, 1800-1891. A.L.s. to [ ]; [n.p., n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
  *48M-224 (5). Gift of Mrs. Charles L. Slattery, 1 July 1948.
- Banda, H. Kamuzu (Hastings Kamuzu), 1905-. Christmas card, signed; Malawi,1986., 2s.(3p.)
  Includes a pasted-down photograph of a group of Malawians.
  *2002M-38. Gift of Dr. and Mrs. Donal A. Brody, 2002.
- Bang, Herman, 1857-1912. A.L.s. to [Hugo ? Heller]; Berlin, 27 Jun 1908., 1s.(2p.)
  *44M-42. Gift of Clemens Heller, 29 July 1944.
- Bangs, Edward A.L.s. to John Locke; Boston, 28 May 1831., 1s.(1p.)
- Bangs, Edward A.L.s. to John Locke; Boston, 2 Sep 1831., 1s.(1p.)
- Bangs, John Kendrick, 1862-1922. A.L.s. to [ ] Adams; [New York] 28 Aug 1902., 1s.(1p.)
- Bangs, John Kendrick, 1862-1922. A.L.s. to Benjamin W. Austin; Yonkers, 20 Jun 1871., 1s.(2p.)
- Bangs, John Kendrick, 1862-1922. 3 A.L.s. to [ ] Baxter:
  - New York, 7 Mar 1919., (1); 1s.(1p.)
  - Same, 17 Mar 1919., (2); 1s.(2p.)
  - Same [1 May 1919]., (3); 1s.(2p.)
    *55M-248. Gift of Charles W. Baxter, 18 May 1956.
- Bangs, John Kendrick, 1862-1922. A.L.s. to Evert Jansen Wendell; New York, 13 Mar 1891., 1s.(1p.)
- Bangs, John Kendrick, 1862-1922. A.L.s. to Evert Jansen Wendell; Yonkers, 9 Jul 1892., 1s.(1p.)
- Bangs, Nathan, 1778-1862. A.L.(3d person) to [ ]; [n.p.] Apr 1856., 1s.(1p.)
- Bangs, Nathan, 1778-1862. A. receipt for money received from Joseph Smith; 3 Jul 1817., 1s.(1p.)
- Banks, Sir Joseph, bart., 1743-1820. A.L. (3d person) to [ ] Bateman; 3 Mar 1820., 1s.(1p.)
  *45M-181(24). Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Banks, Sir Joseph, bart., 1743-1820. MS.L. (retained copy) to [ ]; [London] 11 Jul 1793., 1s.(1p.)
  With brief autograph annotation by Banks.
  *45M-181(25) Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Banks, Sir Joseph, bart., 1743-1820. A.L.s. to [ ]; [London] 7 Aug 1806., 1s.(4p.)
  *47M-373 (6). Estate of Samuel Henshaw. Gift of Mr. and Mrs. Alfred M. Tozzer,; Mrs. Thomas Barbour, and Miss Gertrude A. Thurston, June 1943.
- Banks, Sir Joseph, 1743-1820. A.L.s. to George Chalmers; [London] 7 Aug 1788., 1s.(2p.)
  Norton autographs, 15 Jul 1915.
- Banks, Sir Joseph, 1743-1820. A.L.s. to John Lowell; London, 24 Aug 1818., 1s.(3p.)
- Banks, Mary P A.L.s. to [ ] Walker; Waltham, 29 Apr [ ], 1s.(1p.)
- Banks, Nathaniel Prentiss, 1816-1894. A.L.s. to John A. Lowell; Boston, 1 May 1860., 1s.(2p.) env.
  *45M-181(27). Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Banks, Nathaniel Prentiss, 1816-1894. MS.L.s.to James Morrison McKaye; Alexandria, La., 28 Mar 1864., 3s.(10p.)
  Concerning ability of emancipated slaves to support and maintain themselves.
  Recat. fr. Ms Am 646.
- Banks, Nathaniel Prentiss, 1816-1894. A.L.s. to John Albion Andrew; Waltham, 13 Apr [n.d.], 1s.(3p.)
  *45M-181 (26). Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Banks, Nathaniel Prentiss, 1816-1894. A.L.s. to Samuel Bulkley Ruggles; Washington, 25 Mar 1876., 1s.(2p.) env.
- Banks, Nathan Prentiss, 1816-1894. A.L.s. to James Redpath; [Boston] 9 Apr 1874., 2s.(2p.)
- Banks, Thomas Christopher, 1765-1854. A.L.s. to Thomas Williams; [n.p.] 31 Dec 1806., 1s.(4p.)
- Bannister, Henry Marriott, 1854-1919. A.L.s.to [Edward Kennard] Rand; Rome, 4 Dec 1913., 1s.(4p.)
  *60M-81. Music Dept. Library, Dec 1960.
- Baños, D. Gabriel Ponce de Leon y Lencastre, duke of, 1667-1745. MS.L.s. to Luiz de Vasconcellos e Sousa, 3. conde de Castello Melhor; Madrid, 4 May 1715., 1s. (2p.)
  Gift of John B. Stetson Jr., n.d.